

Rafaella Nicoletti

UX UI DESIGNER

New York City

917-675-3074

rafaella_np@hotmail.com

www.rafaellanicoletti.com

PROFILE

My approach focuses on modern UI/UX branding, patters and a holistic usercentric design. My coding background enables me to integrate responsive design from wireframes to prototype. My experience gives me insight into creating modern and accessible design that cater to user needs. I love to learn and I can usually be found reading on my kindle, about anything.

SKILLS

Project Design

Figma & Sketch

Mobile Design

Design Systems

ADA & WCAG Guidelines

Adobe Creative Suite

Interactive Design

CSS, HTML, JS

WORK EXPERIENCE

EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Foxgroove Interactive

May 2022 - Feb 2023

- Transformed the desktop platform into responsive screens, while ensuring design patterns and flow were maintained. I incorporated animation elements into the mobile screens, enhancing user interaction and engagement.
- · Collaborated in the design system development, assets and components/variants.
- Designed prototypes for enterprise-level SaaS systems in the healthcare industry.
- Implemented modern and accessible design for mobile screens and was part of VQA process.

UX/UI DESIGNER

Freedom Mortgage

Dec 2021 - May 2022

- Created wireframes, high fidelity mockups using inVision and Sketch.
- · Usability testing to validate designs with usertesting.com.
- Worked in Agile environment using Jira, Confluence and designed with ADA & WCAG guidelines.
- Collaborated with Marketing team to ensure consistent brand use across digital channels, developed and maintained digital standards and functional specs and participated in cross-functional digital initiatives.

UX/UI DESIGNER

Home On Call / F&E Media / Freelance

Oct 2019 - 2023

- Freelance for a marketing agency Feb 2023, currently leading the design of a mobile onboarding process from user flows to UI design and journey maps while developing a comprehensive design system to ensure the scalability for future use by other enterprises.
- At Home On Call (02/21-04/21) I created an entire CRM dashboard (500 clients) from scratch with data visualization.
- Designed site maps to improve data organization.
- High fidelity prototype for desktop screen through iterative design process.
- At F&E Media (10/19-02/21), designed their website, UI elements and reports templates that had 10% increase conversion rate, customer engagement up 15% and client retention 100% for 2 years.

EDUCATION HISTORY

BS Business Management

Colorado State University Global

Fullstack Development Bootcamp

Columbia University, NY.

UX/UI Specialization

CALARTS - Coursera

Marketing summer courses

Fashion Institute of Technology, NY.